railsrumble.com 2016-04-06

# Rails Rumble

#### Last revised on July 21st, 2014

### The Big Picture

Rumble Technologies, LLC (“Rails Rumble”) is dedicated to safeguarding your privacy online. The following explains how we will treat information that you may provide to us as you make use of our Site and Services. By accessing our websites (the “Sites”) and accepting the Terms of Service (the “Terms of Service”), you consent to our collection, disclosure, storage and use of certain non-personally-identifying information about you as you use our Sites. We may use this data to better understand our users and build a better service. We can also publish this data, but only if the data will portray a large group of users, not individuals.

We may also ask you to provide personal information, but you’ll always be able to opt out of providing such information.

We can also collect information via cookies, but you can choose not to store these. However, choosing to disable cookies may impact your ability to use our services.

That’s the basic idea, but you must read through the entire Privacy Policy below and agree with all the details before you may use any of our services. This Privacy Policy is effective immediately, meaning that every time you visit our Site or use the Services on our Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy may change over time. Such modifications will become effective immediately upon their posting to this page. It is your obligation to review this Privacy Policy on a regular basis to inform yourself of any changes that may have been made. Your continued use of any of our Services denotes your acceptance of any such modified terms.

## The Fine Print

### Reuse

This document is based upon the [Automattic Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/) and is licensed under [Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike License 2.5](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/). Basically, this means that you can use it verbatim or edited, but you must release new versions under the same license and you have to credit the original authors within the edited version (like in parentheses, perhaps!). Automattic is not connected with Rails Rumble in any way, nor do they sponsor or endorse Rails Rumble or its use of the work.

Rumble Technologies, LLC operates the Rails Rumble innovation competition and makes available to users certain services, including our Sites (railsrumble.com), our blog, our API, and any other software, sites, and services offered by Rails Rumble in connection to any of those (taken together, the “Service”). It is Rails Rumble’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our Sites.

### Users

Like most website operators, Rails Rumble collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each user request.

Rails Rumble also collects anonymized information about how users use our Service. Rails Rumble collects this information for purposes such as quality of service improvement, contact, and feature development / research. From time to time, Rails Rumble may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate for promotional, marketing, and public relations purposes.

Rails Rumble also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Rails Rumble does not use such information to identify its users and does not disclose such information, other than as described below. We may also collect and use IP addresses to block users who violated our Terms of Service.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain users to the Rails Rumble website choose to interact with Rails Rumble in ways that require us to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Rails Rumble gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. Rails Rumble collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the users’ interaction with the Services. Rails Rumble does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. Users can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Service-related activities.

Additionally, some interactions, such as posting a comment, may ask for optional personal information. For instance, when posting a comment, you may be asked to provide a website that will be displayed along with a user’s name when the comment is displayed. Supplying such personal information is completely optional and is only displayed for the benefit and the convenience of the user.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Rails Rumble discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, partners and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to provide Services available at the Sites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors, partners and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country. By using the Service, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Rails Rumble will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

Other than to its employees, contractors, partners and affiliated organizations, as described above, Rails Rumble discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Rails Rumble believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Rails Rumble, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the Service and have supplied your email address, Rails Rumble may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, ask for your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Rails Rumble and competition-related events. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help support other users. Rails Rumble takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

Rails Rumble additionally reserves the right to publish your team name, account username, Rails Rumble’ entries, and certain team and individual profile content on its Sites, blog, and in promotions on third party sites in order to promote the Rails Rumble competition. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you are acknowledging and allowing the information in your profile and/or your competition entries and application descriptions to be published by Rails Rumble or otherwise used for advertising and promotional purposes.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the Service each time the visitor returns to the website. Rails Rumble uses cookies to help it identify and track users, their usage of Rails Rumble Service, and their Service access preferences. Rails Rumble users who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the Rails Rumble website, with the drawback that certain features may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Data Storage

Rails Rumble uses third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run the Service. You understand that although you retain full rights to your data, it may be stored on third party storage and transmitted through third party networks.

### Third Party Websites

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information Rails Rumble collects from you. If you disclose your information to others, such as third party websites that are not affiliated with Rails Rumble, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of your information. For example, by clicking on a third party advertisement and links embedded into user-generated Content, a third party may receive information such as your IP address. Since Rails Rumble does not control the privacy policies or conduct of third parties, you are subject to the privacy policies and user agreements of those third parties. It is your obligation to familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and user agreements of such other websites that you use.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Rails Rumble may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Rails Rumble’s sole discretion. Rails Rumble encourages users to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.

### Questions

If you have question about this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](http://railsrumble.com/contact).
